Eugenics Record Office Records 1670-1964 Mss.Ms.Coll.77
American Philosophical Society
Eugenics Record Office Records
1670-1964
Mss.Ms.Coll.77
American Philosophical Society
330.5 Linear feet
In 1910, the Eugenics Record Office was founded in Cold Spring Harbor, New York, as a center for the study of human heredity and a repository for genetic data on human traits. It merged with the Station for Experimental Evolution in 1920 to become the Department of Genetics at the Carnegie Institution, and under the direction of Charles B. Davenport and later of Albert Blakeslee and Milislav Demerec, it became the most important center for eugenic research in the nation. However with intellectual currents shifting, the Carnegie Institution stopped funding the office in 1939. It remained active until 1944, when its records were transferred to the Charles Fremont Dight Institute for the Promotion of Human Genetics at the University of Minnesota. When the Dight closed in 1991, the genealogical material was filmed by the Genealogical Society of Utah and given to the Center for Human Genetics; the non-genealogical material was not filmed and was given to the American Philosophical Society Library. Following the original order, the ERO Records are organized into thirteen series: I. Trait Files, 1670-1964; II. Trait Card Boxes, 1904-1939; III. Family Traits Card Boxes, 1920-1939; IV. RFT Submitters Card Catalog, 1910s-1930s; V. Record of Family Traits, 1911-1940; VI. Fitter Family Studies, 1913-1936; VII. Field Worker Files, 1911-1926; VIII. Volunteer Collaborators, 1912-1939; IX. Pedigrees, 1828-1926; X. Harry H. Laughlin Files, 1915-1938; XI. Bibliographia Eugenica, 1734-1934; XII. Midget Schedules, 1919-1964; XIII. Index Card Boxes, 1910s-1930s.
Eugenics Record Office.
African American History Note
Eugenics was inevitably entangled in many aspects of American social and political life, and particularly in setting and supporting national policy with regard to immigration and the treatment of ethnic and racial minorities. The ERO Records reflect the eugenical fascination with identifying race-based traits and with locating clear lines of demarcation between the races in terms of behavior, intelligence, and physical characteristics. Race is a particularly clear factor in several files in the Trait Files Series I (documenting the inheritance of purportedly discrete genetic characteristics): "Jamaica anthropometry" (Box 4), "Race suicide and childlessness" (Box 7), "Twins, Negro" (Box 13), "Skin color," "Spotted skin," and "Mulattoes" (Box 26), "Finger prints - Jamaica schoolchildren" and "Woolly hair" (Box 27) and several files under the heading "Race," "Race crossing," and "Negro" (Box 61, 62, 64). The Fitter Family Studies (Series VI) displays an equal concern for racial demarcation, and include some correspondence with the Race Betterment Foundation.
Genetics Note
This collection contains materials which relate to the history of genetics.
Custodial History note
The Eugenics Record Office Papers were donated by the Charles Fremont Dight Institute for the Promotion of Human Genetics at the University of Minnesota in 1992 (Accession #1992-1401ms). An addition to the collection was made in January of 1993 (Accession #1993-55ms).
Glossary of Series Names
The following is a list of the series names as they are currently described in the collection at the American Philosophical Society; as they were described by the Dight Institute; and as they are described in "The Records of the Eugenics Records Office, A Resource for Genealogists" by Thomas H. Roderick, V. Elving Anderson, Robert Charles Anderson, Roger D. Joslyn, and Wayne T. Morris. National Genealogical Society Quarterly. 1994.
Series I: Trait Files Trait Files Specific Trait Files
Series II: Trait Card Boxes Special Studies File Specific Traits Card File
Series III: Family Traits Card Boxes (one box was moved to Series VII) Miscellaneous #2 Family Traits File
Series IV: RFT Submitters Card Catalog Catalogue File not named
Series V: Record of Family Traits Record of Family Traits not named
Series VI: Fitter Family Studies Fitter Family Studies Fitter Family Studies
Series VII: Field Worker Files Field Worker Files Field Worker Reports
Series VIII: Volunteer Collaborators Volunteer Collaborators "VC" or Voluntary ContributorFile
Series IX: Pedigrees Pedigrees; Box #2 not named
Series X: Harry H. Laughlin Files Laughlin not named
Series XI: Bibliographia Eugenica Box #1 not named
Series XII: Midget Schedules Miscellaneous #1 Midget Schedules
Series XIII: Index Card Boxes Index Index
not named (at Center for Human Genetics) "D"; "M"; "W"; Persons File "D" or Detailed Studies File; "M" or Marriage Files; Special Studies on 5x8 Cards; 5x8 Files of Newspaper Clippings
Scope and Contents note
The Eugenics Record Office Papers (1670-1964) contain trait schedules, newspaper clippings, manuscript essays, pedigree charts, article abstracts, reprints, magazine articles, bibliographies, photographs, hair samples, postcard pictures, card files, and some correspondence which document the projects of the Eugenics Record Office during the thirty-four years of its operation. These items are also included on 518 reels of microfilm, which are listed at the end of this guide to the collection.
The papers (382 boxes; 330.5 lin. feet) are divided into thirteen series:
Series I Trait Files, 1670-1964 (65 boxes; 32.5 lin. feet)
Series II Trait Card Boxes, 1904-1939 (13 boxes; 12.25 lin. feet)
Series III Family Traits Card Boxes, 1920-1939 (2 boxes; 2 lin. feet)
Series IV RFT Submitters Card Catalog, 1910s-1930s (13 boxes; 13 lin. feet)
Series V Record of Family Traits, 1911-1940 (1 box;.25 lin. feet)
Series VI Fitter Family Studies, 1913-1936 (5 boxes; 2.5 lin. feet)
Series VII Field Worker Files, 1911-1926 (2 boxes; 1.25 lin. feet)
Series VIII Volunteer Collaborators, 1912-1939 (5 boxes; 2.5 lin. feet)
Series IX Pedigrees: 1828-1926 (1 box;.25 lin. feet and oversized)
Series X Harry H. Laughlin Files, 1915-1938 (5 boxes; 2.5 lin. feet)
Series XI Bibliographia Eugenica, 1734-1934 (21 boxes; 13.75 lin. feet)
Series XII Midget Schedules, 1840s-1964 (2 boxes; 1.5 lin. feet)
Series XIII Index Card Boxes, 1910s-1930s (247 boxes; 246.25 lin. feet)
Biographical/Historical note
The Eugenics Record Office was founded in 1910 and in 1920 merged with the Station for Experimental Evolution to become the Department of Genetics at the Carnegie Institution, in Cold Spring Harbor, Long Island, directed by Charles Benedict Davenport. The E.R.O. was a repository for genetic data on human traits. The Carnegie Institution stopped funding the E.R.O. in 1939, but the Office was active until 1944. The records were then transferred to the Charles Fremont Dight Institute for the Promotion of Human Genetics at the University of Minnesota. When the Dight closed in 1991, the genealogical material was filmed by the Genealogical Society of Utah and given to the Center for Human Genetics; the non-genealogical material was not filmed and was given to the American Philosophical Society Library. A further history of the Eugenics Record Office can be found in the article in Appendix A, "The Records of the Eugenics Record Office, A Resource for Genealogists" by Thomas H. Roderick, Elving Anderson, Robert Charles Anderson, Roger D. Joslyn, and Wayne T. Morris, published in the National Genealogical Society Quarterly. In Series X, in a folder marked "Eugenics Record Office Brochure," there is also an informational brochure that was printed by the Eugenics Record Office, probably sometime between 1910 and 1920.
Carnegie Institution. Department of Genetics; Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory.; Davenport, Charles Benedict, 1866-1944; Laughlin, Harry Hamilton, 1880-1943; Smithsonian Institution. Bureau of American Ethnology..; Station for Experimental Evolution; Algonquin Indians; American Eugenics Society; Apache Indians; Aztecs.; Biology, genetics, eugenics; Carib Indians; Carnegie Institution of Washington; Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory; Cuna Indians; Davenport, Charles Benedict; Eastern Woodlands Indians; Eskimos; Eugenics; Eugenics Record Office; Evolution; Gelatin silver prints; Genetics; Heredity; Human genetics; Indians of Central America--Panama; Laughlin, Harry Hamilton; Photomechanical prints; Plains Indians; Pueblo Indians; Race, race relations, racism; Sioux Nation
- Series I. Trait Files, 1670-1964 (Box Series I: 1-65)
  Scope and Contents note
  Contains materials on single traits, or unit characteristics, considered either heritable in themselves or linked with inheritable traits. Each unit characteristic was assigned and filed by a specific trait ("A") number according to the classification scheme listed in The Trait Book (see Appendix B). Each unit-characteristic file consisted of up to three color-coded folders: a buff-colored folder for collected materials and a red and/or blue folder that contained further references and cross-references. Since the distinctions between the red, blue, and buff folders were not consistent, all three files have been integrated; the current folder labels contain all of the information that was found on the original labels. Materials include E.R.O. trait schedules, manuscript essays, pedigree charts, article abstracts, photographs, correspondence, newspaper clippings, reprints, and magazine articles. The items in each folder were consecutively numbered and stamped with an indexing date by the Eugenics Record Office. Dates on the outside of the folder reflect the dates of the original materials (e.g., the dates of the abstracted articles); if an original date could not be determined, the stamped index date was used. All items were retained in their original numbered sequence, including blank forms, photographs, printed materials, and duplicates of items. If files contained significant photographs or correspondence, a note was made on the outside of the folder and in the folder listing.
  The nature of the unit characteristics themselves is broad, ranging from the temperament of people in various professions to hair color to diseases. Likewise, the nature of materials range from abstracts of medical journal articles to postcards depicting photographs of Coney Island Dreamland Circus Sideshows. Over a hundred files concern studies of twins. The Dight Institute added ten files on Huntington's Chorea, which postdate the work of the Eugenics Record Office.
  Native American Images Note: Black and white photographs of White Cuna Indians, North American Chiefs, and photomechanical prints of Mexican and Alaskan natives. Twenty-three silver gelatin prints from the Smithsonian Institution’s Bureau of American Ethnography of formal, front and side, portraits of Pueblo, Algonquin, Apache, and Sioux men. Taken by an unknown photographer from 1870-1912, individuals are clothed in period dress with some traditional feather, braid, and earring ornamentation. Thirty-seven black and white 3 ¼" square silver gelatin photographs of the White Indians of Panama. As detailed in the World’s Work article "Blond Indians of the Darien Jungle", Richard Olgesby Marsh photographed the natives in their village in 1924. Some photomechanical prints of Aztecs, Caribs, and Eskimos from such works as Harper’s Monthly, New York Times, and World’s Work, dating from 1908-1933. Primarily in folders A:9770-#1, A:9861.
  - A:0 #1 - A:01 #6 (Box Series I-1)
    - New Jersey State Village for Epileptics--Schedules and Forms, A:0 #1 (Box Series I-1)
      - "Key to the present system. Institution reporting.", n. d. (Box Series I-1)
      - New Jersey State Village of Epileptics heredity chart. (Box Series I-1)
    - District of Columbia--Schedules and Forms, 1917; A:0 #2 (Box Series I-1)
    - Schedules and Forms, A:0 #3 (Box Series I-1)
    - Governmental Subsidizing of Parenthood, n.d.; A:0 #4 (Box Series I-1)
    - Schedules from Stature Delineator, n.d.; A:0 #5 (Box Series I-1)
    - Class Schedules, n.d.; A:0 #6 (Box Series I-1)
    - Heredity and Eugenics, A:0 #7 (Box Series I-1)
    - Gordon Strong Heredity Schedules, n.d.; A:0 #8 (Box Series I-1)
    - Clippings, 1920-1934; A:0 #9 (Box Series I-1)
    - Family Pedigree Schedules, 1913-1936; A:0 #10 (Box Series I-1)
    - Development Clippings, 1922-1930; A:01 #1 (Box Series I-1)
    - Development Reprints, 1930, n.d.; A:01 #2 (Box Series I-1)
    - Development [ contains Davenport correspondence], 1922-1923; A:01 #3 (Box Series I-1)
    - Development, 1922-1923; A:01 #4 (Box Series I-1)
    - Development Before Birth, 1920; A:01 #5 (Box Series I-1)
    - [Contains Davenport and Laughlin correspondence], 1921-1930; A:01 #6 (Box Series I-1)
  - A:01 #7 - [A:011] #4 (Box Series I-2)
    - Old School House, Wisley, Ripley, Surrey, England [ contains Davenport correspondence], 1920; A:01 #7 (Box Series I-2)
    - Child's Welfare Association, Washington, D.C., 1920; A:01 #8 (Box Series I-2)
    - Child's Welfare Association, Washington, D.C., 1920; A:01 #9 (Box Series I-2)
    - Abstracts on Development, 1923; A:01 #10 (Box Series I-2)
    - Hastings Manual of Physical Development, n.d.; A:01 #11 (Box Series I-2)
    - Kuprianoff's Development of Recruits During Military Service, 1891; A:01 #12 (Box Series I-2)
    - Index to Development, Anthropometry, and Build, A:01-A:0251 (Box Series I-2)
    - 1921-1932, A:011 #1 (Box Series I-2)
    - n.d., A:011 #2 (Box Series I-2)
    - Tables on Development, 1923; A:011 #3 (Box Series I-2)
    - 1919, [A:011] #4 (Box Series I-2)
    - 1922-1924, [A:011] #5 (Box Series I-2)
    - Anthropometry--Miscellaneous, 1922-1930; A:011 #6 (Box Series I-2)
    - Cross References, n.d.; A:011 #7 (Box Series I-2)
  - A:011a #1 - A:011c #3 (Box Series I-3)
    - Anthropometry: Bowditch Correspondence, 1878-1895; A:011a #1 (Box Series I-3)
    - Weight and Stature of Bowditch Family, A:011a #2 (Box Series I-3)
    - Bowditch, H.P., [1921]; A:011a #3 (Box Series I-3)
    - Bowditch, H.P., 1921; A:011a #4 (Box Series I-3)
    - Bowditch, H.P. "The Growth of Children", n.d.; A:011a #5 (Box Series I-3)
    - Bowditch, H.P. "The Growth of Children", n.d.; A:011a #6 (Box Series I-3)
    - Anthropometry--Albert Govaerts: Belgium, 1922-1923; A:011b (Box Series I-3)
    - Harvard College Physical Records, 1922; A:011c #1 (Box Series I-3)
    - Harvard College Physical Records, 1922; A:011c #2 (Box Series I-3)
    - Harvard College Physical Records, 1922; A:011c #3 (Box Series I-3)
  - A:011c #4 - A:02 #8 (Box Series I-4)
    - Harvard College Physical Records, 1922; A:011c #4 (Box Series I-4)
    - Oberlin College Physical Records, 1924; A:011d (Box Series I-4)
    - Women's Colleges Physical Records, 1922; A:011e (Box Series I-4)
    - Great Britain Anthropometry, [1860-1884], 1911; A:011f (Box Series I-4)
    - Russian Anthropometry, 1911; A:011g (Box Series I-4)
    - Italy Anthropometry, n.d.; A:011h (Box Series I-4)
    - Jamaica Anthropometry, 1928; A:011i (Box Series I-4)
    - Constitution, 1922-1930; A:0115 (Box Series I-4)
    - Retarded Development, 1934, n.d.; A:012 (Box Series I-4)
    - Puberty, 1912-1916; A:0143 (Box Series I-4)
    - Abnormal Development--Hospital Correspondence [ contains photos], 1915-1916, 1930; A:015 (Box Series I-4)
    - Preadolescent Disease, 1923; A:0164 (Box Series I-4)
    - Progeria, 1923; A:0165 (Box Series I-4)
    - Adopted Children, 1914; A:0173 (Box Series I-4)
    - Defective Development, 1919-1922; A:019 (Box Series I-4)
    - Situs Inversus, n.d.; A:0193 (Box Series I-4)
    - 1910-1912, A:02 #1 (Box Series I-4)
    - 1912, A:02 #2 (Box Series I-4)
    - 1913-1914, A:02 #3 (Box Series I-4)
    - 1914, A:02 #4 (Box Series I-4)
    - 1932-1934, A:02 #5 (Box Series I-4)
    - n.d., A:02 #6 (Box Series I-4)
    - n.d., A:02 #7 (Box Series I-4)
    - 1916-1931, A:02 #8 (Box Series I-4)
  - A:022 #1 - A:0251 #3 (Box Series I-5)
    - Acromegaly--Giantism, 1905-1936; A:022 #1 (Box Series I-5)
    - Acromegaly--Giantism, 1915-1931; A:022 #2 (Box Series I-5)
    - Giantism--Pictures, 1919-1927; A:022 #3 (Box Series I-5)
      - Mary Ann Bevan, "The World's Ugliest Woman", n.d.; A:022-16 (Box Series I-5)
    - Short Stature, 1904-1935; A:023 (Box Series I-5)
    - Dwarfism, 1916-1926; A:024 #1 (Box Series I-5)
    - Dwarfism--Pictures, 1919-1929; A:024 #2 (Box Series I-5)
      - Dwarf mother with two young daughters, n.d. (Box Series I-5)
    - Tallness [ contains Davenport correspondence], 1920-1935; A:025 (Box Series I-5)
    - Body Build, 1923-1927; A:0251 #1 (Box Series I-5)
    - Body Build--"Study in Build" by Dr. Davenport, 1923; A:0251 #2 (Box Series I-5)
    - Body Build--Photographs, n.d.; A:0251 #3 (Box Series I-5)
      - Boys body build study, Figure 1, n. d. (Box Series I-5)
      - Boys body build study, Figure 2, n. d. (Box Series I-5)
      - Boys body build study, Figure 3, n. d. (Box Series I-5)
  - A:0251 #4 - A:05 (Box Series I-6)
    - Body Build, 1923; A:0251 #4 (Box Series I-6)
    - Build--Proportions, n.d.; A:0252 (Box Series I-6)
    - Adult Weight, 1920-1923; A:03 (Box Series I-6)
    - Obesity, 1850-1934; A:032 #1 (Box Series I-6)
    - Obesity, 1919-1935; A:032 #2 (Box Series I-6)
    - Obesity--Pictures, 1904-1923; A:032 #3 (Box Series I-6)
    - Obesity--List of Names and Addresses, 1918-1920; A:032 #4 (Box Series I-6)
    - Distrophia Adiposo-Genitalis, 1913-1933; A:0322 (Box Series I-6)
    - Slenderness, 1923-1935, n.d.; A:034 #1 (Box Series I-6)
      Contains 24 pages of data lists pertaining to height.
    - Slenderness--List of Names and Addresses, 1920; A:034 #2 (Box Series I-6)
    - Short and Stout, 1919-1932; A:035 (Box Series I-6)
    - Short Stature, 1920-1925; A:037 (Box Series I-6)
    - Tall and Slim, 1918-1927; A:038 (Box Series I-6)
    - Physical Characteristics, 1924; A:04 (Box Series I-6)
    - Physical Strength and Energy, 1910-1914; A:042 (Box Series I-6)
    - Physical Strength, 1911-1930; A:043 (Box Series I-6)
    - Physical Beauty, 1931; A:044 (Box Series I-6)
    - Fecundity, 1901-1933; A:05 (Box Series I-6)
  - A:051 - A:053 #7 (Box Series I-7)
    - Size of Family, 1903-1938; A:051 (Box Series I-7)
    - Short Interval Between Children, n.d.; A:0512 (Box Series I-7)
    - Race Suicide and Childlessness, 1895-1921; A:052 (Box Series I-7)
      - "Race Suicide Declared Impossible," article on Alexander Graham Bell's views on race suicide and immigration restriction, 1921 May (Box Series I-7)
    - Twinning, 1916-1933; A:053 #1 (Box Series I-7)
    - Twinning, 1921-1925; A:053 #2 (Box Series I-7)
    - Twinning, 1913-1934; A:053 #3 (Box Series I-7)
    - Twinning, 1913-1934; A:053 #4 (Box Series I-7)
    - Twinning, 1919-1921; A:053 #5 (Box Series I-7)
    - Twinning, 1913-1934; A:053 #6 (Box Series I-7)
    - Twinning, 1919-1921; A:053 #7 (Box Series I-7)
  - A:053 #8 - A:053 #15 (Box Series I-8)
    - Twinning, 1913-1934; A:053 #8 (Box Series I-8)
    - Twinning--Abstracts, 1870-1921; A:053 #9 (Box Series I-8)
    - Twinning, 1870-1926; A:053 #10 (Box Series I-8)
    - Twinning, n.d.; A:053 #11 (Box Series I-8)
    - Intermarriage of Twinning Families, 1926; A:053 #12 (Box Series I-8)
    - Twinning--Working Notes, n.d.; A:053 #13 (Box Series I-8)
    - Twinning--Working Papers, 1934; A:053 #14 (Box Series I-8)
    - Twinning--Kimball Family, n.d.; A:053 #15 (Box Series I-8)
  - A:053 #16 - A:053 #23 (Box Series I-9)
    - Twinning--Association Tests, 1931; A:053 #16 (Box Series I-9)
    - Twinning--Association Tests, 1931; A:053 #17 (Box Series I-9)
    - Walter, Mabel R. "A Study of Fraternal Twins", n.d.; A:053 #18 (Box Series I-9)
    - Hinde Twins, 1921-1923; A:053 #19 (Box Series I-9)
    - Twinning, 1916-1934; A:053 #20 (Box Series I-9)
    - Twinning, n.d.; A:053 #21 (Box Series I-9)
    - Twinning, 1914-1931; A:053 #22 (Box Series I-9)
    - Twins--Washington, D.C., 1920-1938; A:053 #23 (Box Series I-9)
  - A:053 - A:053 S #6 (Box Series I-10)
    - Brooklyn Eagle Twin Contest, Oct. 1930; A:053 (Box Series I-10)
    - Twin Schedules, 1914-1927; [A:053 S] #1 (Box Series I-10)
    - Clark of Cleveland, 1914-1919; A:053 S #2 (Box Series I-10)
    - Twin Schedule, 1915-1926; A:053 S #3 (Box Series I-10)
    - Hapgood Twins, 1919; A:053 S #4 (Box Series I-10)
    - Twin Schedules, 1915-1932; A:053 S #5 (Box Series I-10)
    - Prof. Wiggam and Manager of Colonia Theatre, Chicago, IIIinois, 1922-1930; A:053 S #6 (Box Series I-10)
  - A:053 S #7 - A:053 S #14 (Box Series I-11)
    - Twin Schedules, 1917-1934; A:053 S #7 (Box Series I-11)
    - Borden Twins, 1917; A:053 S #8 (Box Series I-11)
    - Twin Schedules, 1917-1928; A:053 S #9 (Box Series I-11)
    - Twin Schedules, 1915-1920; A:053 S #10 (Box Series I-11)
    - Bunce Twins, 1917-1928; A:053 S #11 (Box Series I-11)
    - Twin Schedules, 1917; A:053 S #12 (Box Series I-11)
    - Twin Schedules, 1915-1920; A:053 S #13 (Box Series I-11)
    - Twin Schedules, 1919-1920; A:053 S #14 (Box Series I-11)
  - A:053 S #15 - A:053 S #21 (Box Series I-12)
    - Twin Schedules, 1919-1920; A:053 S #15 (Box Series I-12)
    - Twin Schedules, 1919-1920; A:053 S #16 (Box Series I-12)
    - Twin Schedules, 1921; A:053 S #17 (Box Series I-12)
    - Twin Schedules, 1919-1920; A:053 S #18 (Box Series I-12)
    - Twin Schedules, 1921; A:053 S #19 (Box Series I-12)
    - Twin Schedules, 1922-1927; A:053 S #20 (Box Series I-12)
    - Twin Schedules, 1932; A:053 S #21 (Box Series I-12)
  - A:053 S #22 - A:0533:5658 (Box Series I-13)
    - Twin Schedules, 1932; A:053 S #22 (Box Series I-13)
    - Twin Schedules, 1931; A:053 S #23 (Box Series I-13)
    - Twins: Intellectual Faculties, 1905; A:053:41 (Box Series I-13)
    - Twins: Penmanship, 1915; A:053:453 (Box Series I-13)
    - Twins--Sight and Organ of, 1924; A:053:56 (Box Series I-13)
    - Twins: Ametropia, 1925; A:053:561 (Box Series I-13)
    - Twins--Myopic, 1922; A:053:5615 (Box Series I-13)
    - Twins: Hyperopia, 1924; A:053:5616 (Box Series I-13)
    - Twins--Nystagmus, 1907; A:053:5652 (Box Series I-13)
    - Twins: Teeth, 1924; A:053.61 (Box Series I-13)
    - Twins: Harelip, 1927; A:053.6238 (Box Series I-13)
    - Twins--Ulceration, 1926; A:053.655 (Box Series I-13)
    - Twins--Appendectomy, 1924; A:053.6662 (Box Series I-13)
    - Twins: Parallel Symptoms, 1924; A:053:734 (Box Series I-13)
    - Twins: Reproductive System, 1898; A:053:94 (Box Series I-13)
    - Twinning: Puerperal State, 1908-1914; A:053:96 (Box Series I-13)
    - Twins--Embryonic Annexa: Placenta, 1881-1908; A:053:9612 (Box Series I-13)
    - Twins: Ectopic Gestation, 1914-1917; A:053:9626 (Box Series I-13)
    - Twins: Premature Births, 1859-1908; A:053:96261 (Box Series I-13)
    - Twinning: Eclampsia, 1840-1916; A:053:9628 (Box Series I-13)
    - Twinning: Caesarian Section, 1899-1917; A:053:9641 (Box Series I-13)
    - Twins: Negro, 1833-1918; A:053:9761,3 (Box Series I-13)
    - Twin Monsters, 1921-1933; A:0531 #1 (Box Series I-13)
    - Twin Monsters, 1843-1920; A:0531 #2 (Box Series I-13)
    - Siamese Twins [ pictures], 1926; A:0531 #3 (Box Series I-13)
    - Identical Twins, 1918-1939; A:0532 #1 (Box Series I-13)
    - Identical Twins [ contains Laughlin correspondence], 1865-1935; A:0532 #2 (Box Series I-13)
    - One-Egg Twins, 1866-1927; A:0533 (Box Series I-13)
    - One-Egg Twins--Vitality, 1908-1913; A:0533:07 (Box Series I-13)
    - One-Egg Twins: Defects of Development, 1891-1924; A:0533:019 (Box Series I-13)
    - One-Egg Twins--Fingerprints, 1924; A:0533:131 (Box Series I-13)
    - One-Egg Twins: Psychoses, 1912; A:0533:4 (Box Series I-13)
    - One-Egg Twins: Phobias, 1903; A:0533:422 (Box Series I-13)
    - Twins: Deafness, 1927-1933; A:0533:55 (Box Series I-13)
    - One-Egg Twins--Squint, 1907-1924; A:0533:5658 (Box Series I-13)
  - A:0533:94 - A:053084 (Box Series I-14)
    - One-Egg Twins: Reproductive System, 1891-1906; A:0533:94 (Box Series I-14)